of
the products a bunch of field operators
um uh if you do the backing stage
so this is supposed to be calculated by
uh one over the first function
um and then you have the capacity to
grow and function integral over Phi of x
uh e to that
um
I over H bar I'm going to again omit a
flower noun
um reaction an action is the integral of
the
lagrangian over time or the laguanian
intensity over space and time uh I'm
going to uh separate out the time
components because uh there's some
subtlety just like in the case of the a
simple amount of quantum mechanics it's
going to be some uh subtlety uh with how
you integrate it
um and this L it's an integral level
intensity it's going to be some function
of Y and I think you can buy at the
point x okay amazing expression
if I just have this that's just a partic
option but then I have a additional
instruction of Pi X1 Phi X2
something like that
by example
uh so uh naively that's what we're going
to write
um uh but well you know where when well
here's the thing you have to be careful
about I mean we've encountered this
before but let me remind you
um on the right hand side if I insert
this follow the string of twice in the
path integral
um
uh these files are just integration
variables so by definition the ordering
doesn't matter
uh where is on the left-hand side
I indicated before that uh the letters I
should have interpretation we're going
to understand uh if that works and it's
going to work but if we write a correct
formula
um the last message is supposed to
happen in preparation where this hi-hat
are actually a sequence of operators uh
acne on our helper space so in this case
you take the vacuum State the item with
the first operator the second operation
so forth and then take it overlapping
back that's that's what the left hand
side is supposed to be uh and it was
five hats inside has the kind of
property that we expected to have
generally they will commute with one
another provide this Axis or space like
separate but otherwise they do not
commute if the time like separator
generally does not so on the right hand
side there was no water so this cannot
possibly be true uh as is rhythm
uh and the resolution to that as I have
actually alluded to the quantum
mechanics case uh is that in order for
this formula to be true for the general
ordering
um the operation ordering as written
here with no particular relation amount
x one is two x n I have to interpret
this uh integration in time in this
action exploding here as integration
over a particular path C in the
complexified time plane that is rather
integrating over real time I have to
make the time slightly complex so how
does that work well we've been saying
that's how he works in quantum mechanics
but let me uh remind you
um uh what was going on there
so uh first of all uh first comment is
that as an informed mechanics discussion
we have seen that
um uh is it useful to use something to
think of
um this time part later
um you can insert a complete basis
between these files right and we saw
that if you are to uh how do you
continue this function in the uh to a
complex time in the imagining parts of
the time variables is you know the T1 T2
is such a role of X what would I call x0
um
um then uh you will in order to maintain
this authenticity of the function in
those complexified time variables uh you
have to
um
uh you have to order the Imagine part of
the time in a specific way so so recall
uh
from the
discussion a few less years ago in order
to
uh so to complexify
uh
uh x one zero two zero so all the time
coordinates
um in the way
uh that's uh maintains
uh
elasticity of this function
you know
uh
uh we need to
we we
uh to uh assign
aside
the Imagine part of this x i zeros no
the times in the order
in the order
such that the minus imagine part is
increases right humanitar is decreasing
as you go and write to that so that is
to say
um
X Y zero let's say maybe part of foreign
uh to
uh any
about whether
so the the living the real part of the
arbitrary this is in real time
these are all supposed to be our mission
for real time this by hands are supposed
to be permission operators and loudly
multiplied whatever way I want
um all right
any questions so far
um so uh let me draw a picture so uh to
to illustrate
um uh what's going on and uh and this
these are not all also as you recall
from the discussion of uh just a simple
example quantum mechanics
um there's Contour C this Green Country
C must also approach uh I infinity or
minus I Infinity yes
um so
when you're writing that the expectation
of them each one goes off at the extent
it is analytic
um do you mean that we want the quantity
to be it from bxp.com
as a function of X1 through xn
okay it's an integral these are to some
variables it doesn't mean it makes
doesn't make any sense to say that this
is Andrew I don't even know what that
means because these are these are just
variables labeled by the X these are not
functions okay so that's inside is
Extreme value where the X Y for x n are
parameters of that expression value so
the human value is a function of X1
through x a m that hand side
any other questions
once again if you are a little confused
just look at your notes from
a couple weeks ago it is literally the
same thing I would wrote on the board
before it's just different notations
um
there's a reason I spent so much time on
the basic models mechanics because you
know things otherwise
a little confusing um
um all right so um now let me draw a
picture to illustrate this uh we're just
going to focus on the time coordinates
so real time real part of F0 and imagine
part uh but because our convention for
the uh which rotation uh we are I'm
always going to I think I need to joined
this way before either during the
lecture but I think I wrote this when in
the note that was I posted uh I'm gonna
take this access to be the minus the
manual part of x0 so that things are
oriented kind of in in a way that's easy
to remember otherwise everything will be
upside down
um so
um now I started with
um
uh uh so I started with this the time of
being real but then I want to uh give
assigning some imaginary part of time
only before this current function uh in
a way that maintains electricity
um and um uh by the way I also say that
later at you'll see academics it's
coming on that now that's actually this
to uh only continue to come by time is
not only something I can do there's a
advantage in this mathematical advantage
in doing that the program behaves better
if you give the imaginary Parts in this
way uh for example we'll see later that
uh not very function for real time in
the points X Y X cubed Etc
um if there's space like separated then
everything is fine if you smoother and I
think if they become no lifelike
separated typically they'll be
Singularity the function will have
divergences and things like that
um but these similarities will be
avoided and if you give this
um
uh give the time Point uh some imagine
part is watered in this way so for prior
computations it's often uh most
convenient to start with uh the time
Corners with the smart Imaging cards and
then take a limit and to go back to to
real time and you'll see that there's a
there's a advantage in doing that we'll
come to that
but for now let me just say that we can
make this assignment uh so uh let's say
um
[Music]
those
um uh suppose I picked some arbitrary
bothering okay so let's say I started
this is you know uh if you want D2 uh uh
let's say these three people I started
with these uh the real time but well
they're arbitrary as I said the real
time when originally there was no reason
for any particular order but but you
know but the actual code that I'm
interested in is going to be between
valuable by happy while by happy too if
I had the three if I had before okay and
then I'm going to
but I have to order their imagine time
in a way that uh that minus increasing
and they go from right to left right so
uh for example I can move uh this one
uh
uh all right so so this one has to be
utmost so let's say over here
this is my x one zero hero
um and uh uh this one already it goes
down here that's three zero you know
this one here X4 okay so um so now this
uh a base my prescription so the uh
imagine part of
uh it is the most negative
okay
um this way but now what is the path
um
uh C for the integration in time uh well
uh it has to follow this order so pass
through this X4 first and then pass
through X3 then pass over X2 and lower
X1 and it has to begin at uh I Infinity
but down here this is where uh x 0 goes
to plus I Infinity right
um up there is where X zero goes to a
minus I ability and we said very early
on that this
Infinity imagine time direction is
what's going to select the vacuum state
for us
discussion that was very essential
um and uh uh so that that that's that
now with that understanding of this had
C that device this action that sits on
top of an exponent uh inside the the
path in the world uh then that formula
is expected to be true
um and uh previously we spent a lot of
time discussing the situation where we
heard the under continue uh the real
part of zero where would it take you
know consider the case where the real
part just under zero so all of these X's
are just purely imaginary and that was
the euclidean with the record headed
patterns where we have spent a lot of
time discussing you know that there's
kind of showing the situation where you
straighten up this queen had to be just
a lot of Imagine axis
all right
uh so all of this as you have seen
before but uh now uh in the field Theory
context but yeah pretty much everything
is the same as uh any questions
all right so
um now as you can see uh it is uh going
to be a most convenient to again start
with a situation where we uh and
continue to purely measure time uh
correspond to the fully which rotated of
half of the world or the so-called youth
Lillian packaging World
um
computation and then we'll get
annotating results back to laurencian or
signature real times uh if we need two
uh depending on what kind of question we
want to address uh regarding the
underlying uh vulnerability
uh so uh let me uh first discuss the
euclidean uh or I'm going to continue to
imagine time coordinator I know I'm
going to come back to the real-time
quarterly
okay so uh you know there will be uh
most convenient will be convenient
uh to
uh start with
uh the
euclidia so euclidean correlator
so uh it was
what started with is the neutral it's
like the value of this by hat
um but now I'm going to rewrite this in
the following way uh
I usually notation but I call it if I
had euclidean x one and play it again
X and euclidean so whatever it is so
essentially I'm replacing this if I had
x with uh I think by this one fine where
um uh where X those are here uh x0 is uh
minus i x uh
uh euclidean
B and the x i Vector from 1 to D minus
one is the same as the same as X
euclidean Vector uh so uh in this
location
okay uh
um so
um in this notation
um
uh
[Music]
I can write this as X equivalent vector
and is uh beef component so so this
consists of X including n one and
over to B minus one so this is just a
vector in Infinity space Rd
okay so that's just a uh
let's just a notation so all I'm saying
is that
um uh I'm going to start with this for
later uh I'm going to continue uh x0 so
minus I times some real number x e d and
that is xcp is this one you know so
basically you know this is the same as
the weak rotation procedure
um and uh after performing that
procedure I'm going to label the the my
coordinates of this uh field operators
by the by the position in the euclidean
space the D language space
um and uh April all right I can do this
uh provided that uh this x DB are
ordered in a specific way right so so
this this thing makes sense paper all
right
um uh paper this makes sense if uh these
components of this euclidean uh
positions or so somehow you put it in
time so later I'm just going to refer to
this x0 as the real time or the Horizon
time and this text EV I'll refer to this
euclidean time right so uh provide the
exam time are orders in increasing water
because the minus the magic part in
increasing order uh this identification
would make sense
uh but for the reason I also explain the
quantum mechanical as a simple one
mechanical model context
um
the right hand side if I want to
identify this as a unit on the left hand
side uh I have the order you're going to
time in a specific way
on the other hand uh if I uh switch the
water every time
um well I could
uh
uh on the right hand side I can expand
the definition of the including
correlator also to a situation where the
good time is not ordered in increasing
order how am I going to Define it I'm
just going to Define it to be equal to
the real reordered equivalent quarter uh
and uh
why is that a good thing to do why is
that useful thing to do we'll see that
uh through this examples but this is a
very general fact that one can prove on
very general grounds that actually
um
if you uh
previously defined
the nuclear coordinate function you know
including correlator uh to be by
definition symmetric in all these
operators
um then it actually has good electricity
property that that is to say
um you know I'm going to define the
general coordinator to be an object like
this uh where they could be an object
order right but I'm just going to
declare that uh I can reorder uh
rearrange the ordering here of the five
hats to be such that the equivalent time
is increasing order from right to left
and then that's going to be equal to the
conclusion on the left hand side
uh it turns out that that will be a
prescription that produces a Yukon
coordinator that is fully uh invariant
under the euclidean Symmetry action
which is on these on these points uh in
fact you know one simple way to to see
that
um why that would make sense is that uh
you can let's say compare this to a
situation where you said all the time to
zero okay so so much we said all the
time to zero but the special points are
generic
um if you said all the time to zero then
all these points are space like
separated and the left-hand side are
commutes so it makes sense that at the
right hand side which in this case if
the time is zero if it doesn't do
anything in the right hand side uh is
sort of uh
also invariant and they're permuting
these points
um but
um the the claim is that if I extend the
definition of the equivalent correlator
uh to
um it should be such that it's always
isometric
in fact in general it also has the nice
kind of property uh what we'll see is
that this euclidean query function
actually is going to be a smooth
function generally of these points uh
unless they're coincide as long as these
points are separated generally they say
well Behavior school function and fully
invariant with vertical euclidean
symmetrical
um
okay
any questions about that yes
on the right hand side is it like fine
as like the vacuum expectation value no
no no no there's a this is a uh well I
mean this is a definition right so at
least in the case when they're the time
is ordered this was a definition so we
Define this right hand side as
well that yeah that's what I mean
matters
because otherwise I have not given you
an alternative definition of what is
okay so that's the definition between
correlated this definition as I said
April I only maybe this is a bunch of
words write this down right right here
um the um
uh
um
let me call this communication start
right so so star
uh device
uh the
euclidean
correlator
correlator uh when uh X1 be
is greater than it's two e
greater than
um
uh uh the the this definition
euclidean
or later
uh and
be further
further extend it
to arbitrary
arbitrary
ordering
of x i the these components uh by and
demanding demanding
um this
uh
um
it's invariant
under
permutation
of
we it's already smash
okay
yes I guess what I was asking is like so
this right hand side are we defining it
as a analytically yes yes when I write
that hand side for complex Madness I
mean English language it can only be
performed uh provide you that it's
wondering it wasn't for the imaginary
part of course otherwise it won't be
analytic in general and the condition
would be uh
we'll see this in uh in very explicit
examples uh shortly even in the very
field yes
taking the time which is
uh no particular reason just because I
don't want to Reliable that the the the
the the the numbers on the other
coordinates
there's no there's no degrees
but
um so so once you have performed this
quick rotation
um
I'm going to label the points with the
quality Rd and I'm just calling the
measuring time or the minus measuring
time that these components of the
nuclear equivalence
you can use this but it's just
notifications
uh any other questions
um okay so uh so now so I was trying to
be careful about The annotation but as
before I'm going to often later omit
this subscript E when I talk about
Ukrainian correlator without explaining
explanation and hopefully it will be no
confusion uh when I come to that but
it's a kind of a standard abuse of
notation because later when I call you
can call it I won't keep writing the
subscribe so you will be understood when
they are talking about when I'm talking
about the Lawrence recording
all right
um
okay so uh now in terms of formula
uh
there's supposed to be easier to
calculate and you need uh if I'm talking
about the Clinton correlator now
um
uh once again I'm gonna omit the
subscript E I also open I'll miss the
hats at least
emphasize that
that's implementation anyway
um uh so uh so now uh I can
no this is now
let me just emphasize that
the system
configuration
time
now uh and uh as before I have to
replace this by the
euclidean uh
which is um
uh
uh let me write that in just a second uh
this will be
comedian
where now
uh
um
uh the Spell
including as before uh so Phi it's
Infinity
to emphasize what is going on
um
I
I still keep this subsequence for now
I'm going to drop it later but for now
let me still keep you down from this
part of the board just so that there's
no
it is
all right so once again uh I'm not
really doing anything new compared to
what we our previous discussion about
you know quantum mechanics uh all I'm
doing is adding some additional indices
for the for the variables but on that
there's nothing
okay uh now while I once again well
while I uh uh argue this based on an
integration uh which will rely on
because they're wondering of using time
as you see
um this uh definition uh that extends
that you can put it into arbitrary of
ordering just by requiring that to the
they all commute at the level of nuclear
coordinator uh is compatible with the
swarm of the particle so I don't
actually have to change the form of the
path integral if it had a different
weather range because the right hand
side is my intensity variants these are
just some Americans
yes
um
and please look again why do we have the
integral equities
restricted one is it because
so now I know about the situation where
all these purple points are only imagine
axis and this is blue controller runs
over the measure axis and that's the
same method is equation here am I right
thank you
any other questions
okay uh and now typically uh asking I've
seen the quantum mechanical quality
mechanics example like that typically
um this euclidean version of the action
this whole thing is going to be some
manifestly uh nanometer equality or
found it down below uh and uh for
wildlife videos this whole explosive
exponential will be suppressed okay so
so this this kind of function integral
tend to have a good convergence property
um
so uh
uh no one more point before we get into
exclusive computations
um
um okay so uh
uh it's going to be of interest uh to go
back to
real time to the racing times and uh now
as you have seen there uh I can order
the real time in some Armature way but
there's a particular water ring uh that
would be convenient uh for uh
computation
uh but not only for computation of uh
this kind of coordinate functions but
also for connection to scatter
applicants as we'll see later
um
by the way I should say that uh uh
people have asked me uh you know
partly it was important build Theory I
haven't defined what I mean by particles
upon the filtering yes
obvious kind of particle interpretation
of this personalizing operators for
General incredible Theory so far I'm
talking about some query function uh I
have an introduced military particles
welcome to that and uh only after that I
can discuss the notion of scattering so
that will come in a few lectures
um but there will be an intimate
connection between the notion particles
and scattering uh and amplitudes of
scattering to these query functions
um
uh
anyway
um so uh if you want to go uh from let's
say uh some kind of uh
euclidean uh time configuration let's
say again here I'm joining real part of
time minus imaginary part of time
um suppose I have some weathering like
this it's one zero x two zero
um
uh I want to relate this to real time uh
well uh I'll just have to bring this
back to the real time uh maintaining
some ordering of the the Imagine part
but maintain this ordering of the
imaginary part
uh but there's going to be a
particularly convenient operation that
you can do that is
um so
uh let me start with this screen Contour
um and uh we're just going to rotate
this Contour uniformly
um
um and we're going to end up with the
Contour uh in time uh like this
uh where uh yeah the operation is going
to be literally uh you know rotating all
the points
um and there's at least four lines are
going to end up at uh positions like
uh report when the third one will be
here the fourth one will be here and uh
here and and here
um so if I do this if I uh if I imagine
uh you know in the continuing all the
points according to this uniform
Rotation by the same base
uh obviously uh The Ordering of the
imaginary Parts is maintained
so just before I get to this purely real
Direction
um so uh I can uh if I do that
um because I start with the imagery time
ordered in a specific way uh and then
we're running everything by the same
phase then I'll end up with a comparison
with a real time is also ordered
so if I if I use this construction if I
follow this particular configuration
stand from euclidean correlator with
that what is the time like this I'll end
up with uh I will end up with uh the
real-time correlator uh that this time
okay but in this case it's just a
convenience uh just a convenient choice
that is uh we'll see that there's a
simple prescription and level of a
tactical to actually calculate
um uh time ordering correlator uh by
this uniform rotation prescription uh
but if you want to calculated not time
we'll record it you have to do something
like that which is a bit more
complicated but you can still do it if
you want to okay so at this level uh
so-called time orders correlation
function okay it's just something that
we can Define that is relatively easy to
calculate nothing more than that
okay now let's talk about the actual
computations of these
uh of this correlation
we're going to start with the example of
a pre-filled query already in this case
I think something
uh slowly subtle about these
computations and uh and uh
it's useful to
to understand these uh Clarity before uh
studying interactive theories
uh okay so
for example to begin with we build a
free scalar
field Theory so as we said the
lagrangian density was going to have
with a new you know give you five you do
five uh maximum half unders Square y
squared where you saw that M was the
mass uh particle after the quantization
um so the corresponding with the if I go
to you put your signature by this weak
rotation procedure
um the euclidean uh lagrangian is a plus
one half a sum over commute from one two
b d mu by squared later on I'll make the
summation of course but now at least
you're right it's just for clarity plus
one half and square advisor
is very similar to the discussion of the
harmonic oscillator as you might recall
but now with some additional terms of
involving especially derivatives
okay so let's start with a euclidean
uh content
Point function
um so this will be
and from now on I'm going to drop the
subscript e
everywhere but hopefully that we will be
cleared uh what I'm talking about so pi
x by y so x to the Y are so X and Y are
two points in the clearance space
all right so uh this uh my definition is
a practical procedure is supposed to be
one over Quantum function divided uh e
to the minus the euclidean action uh pi
x piy
um and uh
I'm going to Define this for now as a g
x y
this is also what we call that euclidean
green function
okay
um so now
uh
well we don't have to I mean we have
learned uh several weeks ago well
several weeks ago indeed
um the rules of the capital gaussian
integral so uh
this is still pretty much the same
except that we have some additional
parameters that is despise depend on
maybe the special coordinates
um but if you follow the same rule as
how we can get calculated the
um
uh the gaussian
um happy as well we want to get the
gaussian the excluding values in the
Galaxy integral uh you recall that this
G in this case I mean in this case
indeed this this function
and this two-point function is this G is
nothing but the wick contraction and the
risk potassium is the grid function that
a basic equation
um uh minus box this is a derivative
with respect to X
um plus uh
M squared
uh so that would be the genetic operator
so let me remind you that this is my
action this one integral the x of LP but
if I use apply integration by parts I
can write this as one-half by
by minus box plus M squared five
uh so
uh the the with the contraction the grid
function at some point where we function
is supposed to be the inverse of this
operator
uh and this means that uh it's mostly
the question this I can refunction is
the governor now is the Delta function
in D dimensional as well as to uh just
in time like what we as it works but
that
um you can easily generalize the
derivation we had before so to use this
uh any questions about them
yes what's the Box the box is the usual
uh the physicist
s
p by b x uh
I think I'm usually before yeah
um
any other questions
foreign
x minus y
uh over a square plus M Square let me
just emphasize again that here with this
dot product this is the amphibian
and so later when I talk about memories
have often use the Loyalty in that
products hopefully we'll remember the
definition
thank you
um anyway so all of this was the Supreme
organization of the discussion harmonic
Austin are there any questions
okay
um so
um this expression depending on the
dimension total Dimension D of the space
time uh you could try to uh do the
integral and write this as the expensive
function of x minus y that you uh you
know might prefer but for most of our
purposes this is doesn't give us too
much Advantage so most of the time we're
just going to keep this form of the
Fourier replication because it's going
to be most convenient
um
all right so uh but anyway the point is
that this is in fact a well-defined uh
function uh uh in the coordinates X and
Y that is uh smooth everywhere uh
provided that X and Y is not coincide
If X and Y coincides then this integral
if V is 2 or higher as you can see this
integral was diverge that is in contrast
to the case of the bond behind the
simple Quantum model where we have
equals one in that case this thing was
finite at zero time but now if X and Y
cosine generally will diverge but uh but
that's okay
okay
uh any any questions before I discuss
the uh continuation of this uh back to
laurencian signature
okay so uh now uh we're going to
uh
go back to real time
so
let's do this
um
okay so now we want to
another continue
to real time
um and we're going to follow the the
procedure that I indicated in this
picture
okay so now let's turn that picture into
some equations
so um
every time I wrote
you're going to type XD
and remember that in real time
would be minus i x d right another let's
say the Lord didn't have a minus ixb of
course it's very imagination we call it
the real time but that was the second
time
so this was supposed to be the X zero
um and uh then there's also y0 which
would be minus i y d
so
um I'm starting with a euclidean
two-point configuration uh so XB and y d
are both real to begin with and
therefore minus i x D minus i y d lies
somewhere on the Imagine axis
uh and if I perform this rotation uh I'm
that means I'm going to write this as
something times a real number T
sometimes number T Prime uh with some
base e to the minus I Alpha uh it's the
same phase
all right so uh uh so after that
um
uh t t Prime will be real
uh and I'm gonna order them the research
that is better than G Prime
uh hopefully I got a sign for x and
Alpha is going to uh vary from pi over 2
to just above zero
uh so this is we're going to agree with
what I drew in this diagram here uh that
is uh you see if I uh start with Alpha
equals pi over 2
and so this is minus I this is minus I
and x b is going to be greater than y d
um where for that uh
interpolation of as the Laurentian
two-point function with it without pivot
ordering right
um so that's all I want
so so I'm starting at alphabet with
minor two that's the first
and then I'm going to follow that
picture I'm going to vary Alpha
continuously from pi over 2 to just
about
uh if I do that I'm going to end up at
this uh green line here
uh so that at the end toward the end
um uh okay so the uh the minus imagine
part would be the order of the minus
emergent part should be preserved and
and I think so that that will be true so
let's see so uh so this will be uh but
now is uh slightly above zero right this
is y minus I times Epsilon some small
relative Epsilon and if the t is well in
this way it is the the minus minor part
is is ordered but this comes so that's
the that's the correct whatever anyway
verify this uh careful yourself
um okay so let's see uh let's see what
happens to this function let's follow
this
okay
um now I think probably many of you have
never actually seen uh how to continue
how to continue a function defined by
the engine room so this is example by
where you see how to do this uh you see
uh if I didn't have the integral if I
just have this 80 grand uh it's obvious
how I'm gonna give you because this
exponential function by that this is
analytic so you just plug in the value
and you get it but things are not uh
quite so simple necessarily for the
integrated expression
um here's something that can happen so
for example uh let's say uh you have a
sound function that's defined by some
Contour integral so in some variable
let's say this is a variable could be k0
you get another function is some other
variables such as this G here G of X
let's say
um and you want to ask uh is it the
result analytic in X Africa
uh now uh if the integrand is another
everywhere along those contour and it
converges
Amazing World
um then that property
the end history will be preserved
another
um the problem will occur
if the potential problem can occur uh if
the integrand itself such as this one
over H bar plus N squared you might have
some pole some Singularity somewhere
else from complex blank why would that
be a problem well if Nepal is away from
introducing countries uh well you know
you never touch that ball there's no
problem
but what can happen is that as you want
to continue with the private such as
text the small can move
then you have a potential problem right
if you move to the Contour
then the integral will be LD bind and
you it will not be obvious what the
integrated function remains analytic
however if the power moves to the
Contour it doesn't mean the Innovative
result is not analytic because notice as
I have to insist on using this Contour
you could have before the Contour Maybe
uh as you know if this
is
the result is the same so in person
okay
analytics but you had to work with this
before
uh in this way you cannot continue the
integrated result as a function in X for
example provide you that there is a
situation where you can look at a
pinched by our parents as long as that
doesn't happen you're still responding
um the situation where you get we can't
get a pinched by her because it will
occur and sometimes in the problem two
of the current problem says but uh um
but you you will see how to deal with
badly explicitors
um so uh here so anyway the the lesson
is that uh you it's very important as
you want to continue in this way right
you're going to make x d and y d complex
now but you have to be very careful to
deform the Contour to ensure the
individual first of all converges and no
pole has the control
as long as you can do that the result
will remain analytic
okay so let's try that
so we're gonna take that top expression
but G
uh so so once so I can do this right so
we're gonna set uh uh mine so so in the
in the uh oh yeah
presentation
of G that's why uh
so if in order to okay
so we're going to take the X and Y
uh which were uh we're going to focus on
XD and yd because that's the those are
the variables we're continuing where
we're moving I'll come explain so uh
we're going to start with X and Y E
being a real that was how it was defined
to begin with and now we're going to
make it complex by taking Alpha to
starting with pi over 2 and then Focus
down
um once you make HD and widely complex
you have to worry
because what is this and just write this
out
all right this
this thing is the same as e to the i k
letter
that the D minus one dimensional plus I
K D X B minus y d
all right so if I make SDM yd both
complex
uh you might think that there's a
problem
the problem is that Katie was real to
begin with so if XB and why they acquire
about the fire some imagining Parts as
they do here
this integral this exponential is going
to blow up in One Direction already
so that sounds bad you know I say that
like not to continue because
um because uh uh this integral is
Divergence but that's not correct
because what I'm trying to continue is
not the integral itself is the result of
it just because
itself cannot be directly applied
doesn't mean that the function can be a
negative because I'm free to rotate the
country
so
um this integral uh is uh uh you know
provided that uh
providing that the signal converges at
Infinity uh along with the Contour uh
I'm free to wrote the Contour as I uh
perform uh the imagery part of X and Y
okay
um so uh
simultaneously so that KD times XC minus
y d remains real
uh we can do that by studying uh minus
sign KB which would be e to the plus I
Alpha uh
okay zero
uh and uh take page zero uh so ranges so
Canada ranges from uh from uh minus the
ability to Infinity uh with all the real
axis
once again I started with Alpha equals
pi over two uh and the alpha goes down
this is the Same album right so if I do
this
uh you know this P to the minus i o
please I plus I have a cancel out and
exponent uh and uh so uh the KD times x
minus y v will remain real
uh so if I do that uh what is the result
of this expression so this I can now
write as uh well so first of all so
I have any question over
dkd and the PK vector
2D
2 by 2 over 2 y to the D
um I'm going to replace uh the KB by I
times this right so so if I change the
variable it has come to integral so it's
time I equals
um
uh
okay so uh you will have to be a little
careful about the orientation uh because
if I follow this procedure uh before I
was integrating KD from minus infinity
uh to Infinity
uh but here
uh now if I if I write this uh
did you find this in terms of k0 in this
way uh at Alpha equals pi over two this
is plus I here so I'm actually uh you
know the k0 agrees with kdf plus sign
um so in order to write this application
the different individuals
I have the same concept of that
scientists so this minus sign here
um and I'd love 80 grand uh what do I
have after this
substitutional variables uh I have into
the i k Vector dotted with X Vector
minus y Vector uh that plug into KD is
uh uh my I times this the XD minus y d
is uh I times that so there are two eyes
I get a minus sign so this is now
starting to look like a lowercase unit
product so minus minus i k zero uh T
minus t y
yeah I've got uh case Vector square plus
N squared but then here I have KB uh
squared another KD squared I'm going to
again replace with this rule right so so
then that gives me uh K 0 squared minus
E to the 2i alpha
okay so
um
I I claim that this is the actual result
of that recognition uh for any Alpha in
this range
uh so by construction this will preserve
the analyticity of the resulting
function the function of x
or a function of uh
and if I take the limit
all the way down to zero because T will
agree with that zero and T Prime will
agree with Y zero at the lorenzian time
actually
okay
uh now uh there's something I forgot to
check but then I have to make sure not
only that into it has a converge that
the endpoints of the Contour
um I also have to ensure that no pole
pass through the Contour
uh like in the picture earlier now is
that the case
uh well the only thing in the check here
is whether as you as Alpha ranges from
pi over two to zero
um with the denominator ever vanish
well let's see uh the case Vector square
plus M Square this thing is always
positive
okay so uh and k0 is uh by construction
okay zero is integrated over
the real line okay there is always real
k0 square is always positive
um and so
this quantity here
um
so we start with uh Alpha being pi over
two right we start with a situation
where F of n power two this this is uh e
to the iPad this is minus minus one so
so we have two minus sign okay so we
started with this thing being positive
in real
generic Alpha between zero and however
two uh this is complex
okay uh and uh you can you can easily
verify right that's the imaginary part
of this number of actress before you
Alpha reaches back down to zero
so that's why actually I wrote zero plus
we said it's gonna stay a little bit
above zero as long as Alpha stays a
little bit above zero this thing never
vanishes uh sorry the Imagine part of
this difference
imagine in part
uh
non-zero is always on zero for uh Alpha
between
pi over two and zero
so as long as I don't go all the way up
down to zero I'm safe because this
geometry is never single the function
remains analytic
uh so that that's consistent with our
definition of recognition uh we would
run into a bit of trouble if we
literally set Alpha to zero
minus k0 squared and you see the
integrand will diverge for some value
okay zero and the United States
this expression would make no sense but
I was careful I wrote this one down to
zero plus so you're not supposed to take
Alpha to literally easier as long as you
approach Zero from above uh then this
elasticity is maintained
uh any questions so far
all right
um
now uh in practice for Value computation
um okay so so what is the conclusion
here the conclusion here is that in
order to uh obtain so so what is this
the result of this supposed to be now
the thing we want to calculate uh is uh
with the Laurentian
um
for your function
um uh with the x0
greater than what
um
uh and that result uh would be obtained
by this procedure uh if you uh carefully
take the limit that is
um you are simple uh yeah so what have
we achieved uh well again what we say is
that you you don't take this expression
which is valid for Alpha uh slightly
above zero and if you do the integral
first and then they also go to zero
limits there you are say but you cannot
do the other way around okay if you take
it output to zero first and then delete
five
all right so you have to be so careful
uh now in practice it's not very
convenient to always keep this Alpha
around at the end of the day uh most of
these like this free factor is not going
to be very important because if you take
Alpha to zero the three package is
supposed to one so that actually doesn't
matter it's mostly this this happen here
it doesn't matter uh in practice
um uh actually all we need to do is to
in order to get the correct answer for
real time uh is to just to uh you always
do is to ensure that this pole never
acquire across the Contour so so yeah
well in that language but but the point
is that
um uh even before generating Alpha
you know this integrand will have a pole
somewhere it's just not along the real
case or axis this pole is going to
approach real major axis like that
picture we take Alpha to zero
more explicitly where is it
that in the grand the 80 grand
right the Instagram
has a whole
e to the minus Pi Alpha
plus minus uh square root of a squared a
matrix right as suppose uh these
positions and finally you should do this
on the picture I think it's it
illustrates
better
um
okay
uh like this
so uh
let's say this is the complex
k0 thing
so this is the real axis
uh and this is like imagine axis
uh and uh
um or both
are these
um so for Alpha siding upon zero e right
um this is either going to be down here
or up there so these are the hooks
following the real axis
all right so in this procedure
um as long as you know as long as the
polls do not cross the real axis you're
okay
um but uh but but if you take it up into
zero just always will get to real assets
but that's what's happening
okay so
um now uh for problem computation if
you're only interested in the result for
real time
um it suffices to uh
uh use the so-called if the prescription
uh that is you just add by hand a small
imaginator
um so that to ensure that the fact that
Paul never crossed the Contour in this
case you're enjoy your contour and then
then you need to say alphages to zero at
the end of zero you have the sum by
Epsilon in the diameter and you can do
the interval first and then take if you
take absolute zero at the end uh if
necessary and to obtain the actual
result that you want so
um
so let me just write the um the formula
for that for that
um is basically we're just going to make
the same formula here and then output
zero but we're going to add a actually
we're going to add a minus I Epsilon the
reason we're going to add minus I
Epsilon is uh you see uh
the key here for the alpha standing at
zero is that it has some small imaginary
parts and that ensures that this
government never vanishes uh we just
need to make sure that we have the right
sign for that imaginary parts and when
Alpha approaches zero uh the magic part
from above the major part of this
minus sign is always negative so for
this we did minus I so that looks like
minus I Epsilon so the 10 is that if you
actually calculate this integral
into that I okay
zero there's Zero moves y zero over
minus a zero squared plus K Vector
squared plus N squared minus I Epsilon
uh
if you calculate into a first and then
take Epsilon to Zero from above you'll
get the same results as uh this
procedure when you take Alpha zero
we're the same result so uh so that's
where the ifs infrastructure comes from
we come from doing this recovery uh and
I don't have to keep uh always keeping
the alphas because iot prescription will
be sufficient uh to produce uh the
correct answer
um and uh in fact uh this uh procedure
the procedure that we use for this
derivation uh Works
um both for uh uh so this formula is
going to work uh as is written uh if x0
is greater than y zero uh it would also
work for x0 less than y zero
um but if I exchange the order of this
by hands
um so it generally it's going to or make
sense for time orders uh
two-point function where there's no
texture here
means that
this location is that he I had
uh X if I had Y is is defined to be
if I had X
I had y
if x0 is greater than y zero then it's
going to be if I had y
I had X
if uh y zero
around X zero is less than one
repeat the same derivation and you find
the same form we
um
and uh
usually we can kind of combine this and
write this as a integral in the
laurencian vector
can you
[Music]
x minus y but very importantly both this
and this dot is our Laurentian or the
vicause
okay so if you compare this formula
so that formula I wrote over there they
look uh almost the same with a few uh
small but very important differences
first of all the fact of minus eyes in
the front Okay that's a little weird but
that's the way it is comes out of this
derivation and also uh well the dot
product is different right there there's
you have a nucleus product here in the
lorenzial products but importantly I
have a minus I Epsilon without my my
antioxidant this integral would be
ill-defined this integral makes no sense
because it's going to diverge I want at
one point where the pole like on real
axis can be your defined but whether I
have to learn I always avoid the part if
we want to Define we're supposed to
interpret this expression as the F2 Goes
To Zero from above limit of that
integral
yes
what I'm trying to say is that this
application will calculate uh
yeah this
you can continue this function however
you want the question is what is the
correlator that is actually calculate
right the importance you have that the
acid calculates your procedure you have
to maintain the ordering of the
measuring time
in order for the beginning
yes in order for an acquisition to agree
with the word support it when you said
that in person
at the beginning
[Music]
um
so you know
these things are basically but they can
be confusing as you can see it's very
important that you think this through
and get this straight
um so uh
and any other questions about about this
uh continuation procedure
uh now actually another thing about it I
wish I had to assign the homework on
this but I will I guess I'll invite you
to check for yourself
um
here and you know what if I had uh it is
in terms of the creation and
international operators okay diagram hey
uh so you can use the definition and
this plug-in verifies this is true
okay so I could have just used the
definition of by hand in terms of
expression if I had in terms of a and a
dagger I literally calculated this and
rewrite in terms of this integral uh but
then it will assume that everything just
came out the blue uh you could do that
but this is kind of a uh explanation
from the point of view of panic
activation of the euclide
um
let's see same
uh let's see
uh yeah I guess I'll just stop here I
think at this point
um if you know the ukulele function uh
and which is the the same method which
contraction between a pair of eyes so by
the rule of Wick contracted you should
be able to do the problem too in that in
the distance because all of that was
phrased in the language
complete by calculation we will come to
the interpretation of the results of
that later next lecture I'm going to
discuss uh these kind of great functions
in a general one bill not just the
previous
thank you
[Music]
opportunities